Susan Rindt, PsyD

Markdown -> PDF, HTML, and more http://github.com/drrindt/resume

OBJECTIVE

FIXME: update this It is my intention to develop a private clinical practice while continuing to provide treatment and services in both hospital and community-based settings. At this time, I provide individual therapy, group therapy, and psychological testing services to diverse populations. My clinical interests and expertise include: trauma; physical and sexual abuse; acute psychiatric disorders; grief and loss; substance abuse; relationship issues and communication patterns; anxiety and eating disorders; specific learning difficulties; and adolescent, developmental, and geriatric issues.

EDUCATION

California School of Professional Psychology (San Diego, CA)

Psy.D. Clinical Psychology—Family Track, March 2002

California School of Professional Psychology (San Diego, CA)

M.A. Clinical Psychology, June 2000

University of Stirling (Scotland, UK)

B.Sc. Psychology, June 1998

Certifications

- ► Certified Prolonged Exposure Therapy clinician
- ► Certified Cognitive Processing Therapy clinician

CLINICAL EXPERIENCE

Director of Military Programs, April 2008—present

Contractor to Aurora Behavioral Healthcare, San Diego, CA

- ► Program development, organization and management of intensive inpatient residential treatment program for active duty service members.
- Manage a staff of 15 directly and oversee operations of multiple other departments
- ▶ Provide direct therapy treatment for PTSD and Substance Use disorders as well as multiple psychiatric and personality disorders.
- Clinical supervision and training of licensed professionals working in this program
- Administrative duties including department accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, business development and assisting in personnel decisions.
- ► FIXME: Marketing and outreach to military bases through the western United States, Alaska, and Hawaii
- ► Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department
- ► **FIXME**: some mention of working with military insurers (Tricare, etc)

Director of Psychology, April 2007—present

Contractor to Aurora Behavioral Healthcare, San Diego, CA

- ► Clinical supervision and training of 7 predoctoral and 3 postdoctoral interns in group therapy, individual therapy, testing batteries, and initial assessment.
- Group and individual therapy with acute inpatient and outpatient psychiatric patients.

► Administrative duties including departmental accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, and assisting in personnel decisions. Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department.

Clinical Private Practice/Hospital Consultant, August 2003—present

Locations: Coronado, CA / Del Mar, CA / La Mesa, CA

- ► Treatment modalities: Individual psychotherapy using a variety of therapeutic techniques including cognitive behavioral therapy, family systems theory, and insight-oriented modalities. Brief therapy and long term models used where appropriate.
- Consulting and Training Services: Individual psychotherapy using a variety of therapeutic techniques
 including cognitive behavioral therapy, family systems theory, and insight-oriented modalities.
 Brief therapy and long term models used where appropriate
- Hospital Privileges: Bayview Behavioral Health/Paradise Valley, Sharp Mesa Vista, Alvarado Parkway Institute

Assistant Director of Psychological Services, August 2003—January 2004

Alvarado Parkway Institute, La Mesa, CA

- Clinical supervision and training of 6 predoctoral and 3 postdoctoral interns in group therapy, individual therapy, testing batteries, and initial assessment.
- Group and individual therapy with acute inpatient and outpatient psychiatric patients.
- Administrative duties including departmental accounting, case management, treatment team, utilization review, and assisting in personnel decisions. Liaison between nursing staff, social work department, utilization review, psychiatrists, and the psychology department.

Psychological Assistant, August 2002—January 2003

Alvarado Parkway Institute, La Mesa, CA

- Group and individual therapy with acute psychiatric patients.
- ► Training and supervision of psychology interns.
- ► Case management using a multidisciplinary team approach. Psychological testing batteries.
- Liaison between nursing, social work, utilization review, psychiatrists, and psychology departments.

Psychological Assistant, September 2001—August 2002

Switzer Center School, Torrance, CA

- Individual counseling with learning disabled and emotionally disturbed children and adolescents.
- Case management. Achievement and neuropsychological testing.
- ► Individual education program development.
- Parent and collateral contact liaison.

Psychology Intern, July 2000—June 2001

Bayview Hospital, Chula Vista, CA

- ► Group and individual therapy with acute psychiatric patients.
- Case management using a multidisciplinary team approach. Psychological testing batteries.

Psychology Practicum, August 1999—June 2000

EYE Crisis and Counseling, San Marcos, CA

- ► Individual and group therapy with children, adults, and families primarily involving issues of sexual abuse.
- Psychological testing.
- Administrative functions.

GENERAL EXPERIENCE

Founding Member, Vice President and CFO, July 2010—Present

Psychiatric And Therapeutic Health Services, Inc., Del Mar, CA

- ► Managing partner of a clinical mental health group practice serving primarily military families.
- ► Responsible for clinical oversight, marketing, and day-to-day operations

International Student Mentor Program Coordinator, August 2000—August 2001

California School of Professional Psychology, San Diego

- ► Mentoring students from overseas with diverse backgrounds
- ► Supervision of other mentors (13 in total)

Senior and Childrens' Representative, March 1993—October 1995

Thompson Holidays, Ibiza, Spain

 Responsible for the control and maintenance of holiday venues and care of both vacationing children and their parents

Assistant Manager, August 1989—March 1993

B & Q, Plc., Glasgow, Scotland, UK

► Personnel, administration, and systems manager. Staff trainer. Responsible for 70 staff and 54,000 sq. ft. of retail space.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant, August 1999—May 2001

California School of Professional Psychology (San Diego)

- ► Dissertation Orientation
- ► Developmental Psychology
- ► Social Psychology

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Care Assistant, August 1990—June 1997

Craighalbert Centre, Glasgow, Scotland, UK

Attended to severe and profoundly mentally and physically handicapped youths, particularly autistic children.

Care Assistant, March 1993—October 1994

Spanish Youth Action Group, Ibiza, Spain

Assisted with outreach program for adolescent substance abusers

AWARDS

FIXME: Military program award (or was that Aurora)

BEST Scholarship

BUNAC, London, UK, 1998—2000

► Won \$10,000 scholarship for two years of post-graduate study in the United States from the British Universities North America Club (BUNAC).

Education Abroad Program (EAP) Participant

University of Stirling, Scotland, UK, 1996—1997

► Won fully funded scholarship (tuition and expenses) to study psychology overseas at the University of California, Irvine for one year.

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND CONTINUING EDUCATION

FIXME: all your military CEs

Aging and Long Term Care, Rekindling Desire in Couples, 2005

HIPPA Made Friendly, 2004

Treatment Planning Made Simple, 2004

Spousal Abuse: Assessment, Detection, and Intervention Strategies, 2004

Principals and Practices of Clinical Supervision, 2003

Human Sexuality, Domestic Violence, Chemical Dependency I and II, 2002

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

American Psychological Association

British Psychological Society

California Psychological Association

San Diego Psychological Association